Guide to the Nelson J. Shaulis papers, 1941-1986.
Shaulis, Nelson J. papers, 1941-1986
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nelson J. Shaulis papers, 1941-1986.
22-2-3140
Nelson. Shaulis
33.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Diaries, Manuscripts, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Reports, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alphabetical correspondence, files relating to European trips, manuscripts, slides, and photographs relating to his research on siting vineyards, grapevine physiology, vineyard mechanization and management, mineral nutrition, rootstocks, and canopy microclimates. Also research pertaining to an unfinished book.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Viticulture, New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, Geneva.
Nelson Shaulis graduated with a B.S. in horticulture and an M.S. in agronomy from Pennsylvania State University. He received his Ph.D. from Cornell in 1941. He served as a soil conservationist with the USDA Soil Conservation Service from 1938 to 1944, while he was also an instructor and assistant professor of pomology at Penn State. In 1944, he was appointed assistant professor of pomology at Cornell, and became professor of pomology and viticulture from 1948 to 1967. He retired as professor of viticulture in 1978. His major contributions to the grape industry included a training system for grapes called the Geneva Double Curtain (GDC), which he initiated at the Experiment Station in 1960 and with growers in 1964. He also helped to develop the mechanical grape harvester. Shaulis was named a fellow of the American Society of Horticultural Science in 1972 and in 1997 was the recipient of the Merit Award given by the American Society for Enology and Viticulture (ASEV), the highest award of the society. He also received Merit Awards from the Society of Wine Educators, the American Wine Society, the New York State Wine and Grape Foundation, and the National Grape Cooperative.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Alphabetical correspondence, files relating to European trips, manuscripts, slides, and photographs relating to his research on siting vineyards, grapevine physiology, vineyard mechanization and management, mineral nutrition, rootstocks, and canopy microclimates. Also research pertaining to an unfinished book.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Shaulis, Nelson.; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.
Subjects:
Wine and wine making--New York (State); Wine industry--New York (State); Grape industry--New York (State); Viticulture--New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Pom and PM followed by a number indicate 5.5” x 7.75” negative envelopes with photos of plants, fields, or charts/tables. Only a very few also have slides or negatives enclosed.
Portions of unpublished book are located in Boxes 26, and in various folders throughout the collection which include "book" in the title, non-exclusively.
Colored, but blank post-it notes were attached so some boxes of slides but no key available. These notes were left attached to the first section heading card in the box.
RELATED MATERIALS
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
Related material located in collection #8132, Chisholm-Ryder mechanical grape harvester records.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a finding aid for Boxes 1-22, also a bibliography of Shaulis' publications.
- Correspondence-DC Trellis Systems, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Juice, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Misc-Correspondence, Clippings, Growth Study, Viticulture, 1948-1981 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Herbicides-Gen’l., 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Concord Grape Maturity and Flavor, Environmental Factor Study etc., 1961-1968 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Also remakrs about the Concord grape prepared by Richard Wellington at teh request of Walter Taylor for the opening of the Taylor Museum in Hammondsport, July 3, 1967.
- Equation and Outline, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Yield of Grapevines in NYS, 1970-1979 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Vineyard Suppliers, Equipment etc., 1978 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- N.Y. Viticulture-Complex of Research-Oriented Decisions, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Book-Tools and Machines, 1969-1978 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Misc-ASAE, Photos, Mechanization of Shoot Positioning, 1977-1989 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Hunger Signs, Paper, 1st Manuscript (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Delaware Petioles, Bibliography-Iron Nutrition etc., 1960-1987 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Hatch Vineyard, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 14)
- Fe Mat (Iron Materials), 1960-1982 (Box 23, Folder 15)
- News Paper Clippings, Inst. Tech. Advisory Committee Meeting etc., 1951-1984 (Box 23, Folder 16)
- Mechanization (Box 23, Folder 17)
  Mechanical harvesting products, impact on grape flavor, etc..
- Soils (Box 23, Folder 18)
  West Virginia study
- Grafting and Pruning (Box 23, Folder 19)
- The Relation Between Direction of Growth and Vigor of Grapes by A. M. Burroughs, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 20)
- New Zealand Material (Box 23, Folder 21)
- Grape Growing Areas (Box 23, Folder 22)
  Grape Belt, Ohio, Mesilla Valley New Mexico, Virginia, Minnesota, New Hampshire
- Miscellaneous Notes (Box 23, Folder 23)
- Terminology Project (Box 23, Folder 24)
  Definitions.
- Glossary Project (Box 23, Folder 25)
  Definitions and quotes.
- Grape Production and Cost Data, 1930s-1960s (Box 23, Folder 26)
  U.S. and Canadian grape production data as early as 1909. 1945 Grape census. Also includes Annual Finger Lakes Grape Tour data from the 1940s, published in 1949, inludes the following vineyeards, Elvira, Granby, Beers, Fox, Kimbar (at the German prison camp), Depot, all these were owned by Widmer Wine Cellars.
- Grape Phenology (Box 23, Folder 27)
- American Wine Society (Box 23, Folder 28)
- Clippings (Box 23, Folder 29)
  Many from the Grape Belt
- Statistics, Wang 700 (Box 23, Folder 30)
- Shaulis related publications (Box 23, Folder 31)
- New York State Agriculture 2000 Project (Box 23, Folder 32)
- Geneva Double Curtain and Other Trellising Materials (Box 23, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Brochures, Pamphlets, Publications (Box 23, Folder 34)
  Includes issues of Cellar Notes and an article on Wine Growing in the Finger Lakes from the American Wine Society Journal.
- Publications on climate and vineyard growth in developing wine areas (Box 23, Folder 35)
- Miscellaneous Grape Research Publications and preprints (Box 23, Folder 36)
  Includes paper on Promising New Grape Selections form the New York State Breeding Program with descriptions of many crosses. Also papers oninterstock and vigor grant proposal, heat treated riesling, Ethrel trials at Taylor vineyard, Alar, American Journal of Enology and Viticulture Guide to Authors. Also a bilbiography of works, possibly used in class Horticulture 355.
- Material from grape related conferences (Box 23, Folder 37)
  Includes, International Symposium on Cool Climate Viticulture and Enology at Wine Expo '84, NEC-9 minutes.
- Material on Grape Growing in Virginia (Box 23, Folder 38)
- Gordon S. "Stan" Howell material (Box 23, Folder 39)
  Sabbatic report and report to Michigan Viticultural Advisory Committee.
- Materials on Pests (Box 23, Folder 40)
  Phylloxera, Drosophila
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 41)
- Cold Climate Material (Box 23, Folder 42)
  Includes letter to John Einset from J. A. Savignac of Maison Champagneur in Joliette, Quebec Canada about their vineyard varieties.
- Viticulture black and white photographs (Pom cards) guide (Box 24, Folder 1)
  See box 25 for Pom cards with headings listed through Potted vines
- Federal Crop Insurance, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Grape Production, 1920-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  Most contents from 1977-1980
- Light Distribution, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Grape Prices Paid By Some New York Processors In 1976, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Crop Loads (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Phenology, 1975-1980 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Australian Work – Field A, Peter May and Don Alexander, 1960s-1970 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Australian Work – Field F (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Reflections on New York Viticulture Speech, Rochester, NY, January 17, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Press Record request for photo, Ministry of Agriculture, New Zealand, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Society of Wine Educators annual award article, Wine Educator’s Chronicle, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Viticultural seminars letters of support, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Nelson Shaulis resume, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- New York Viticulture: Past and Present – An interview with Nelson J. Shaulis, Wine East, draft, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Yield of ripe, sound grapes per unit area land, ca. 1989 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Uptake of nutrients, ca. 1980 (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Letter from Lyndie M. Thomas, American Society for Enology and Viticulture regarding annual meeting program, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 18)
- Vit Sort, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 19)
- Widmer Vineyards, 1976-1985 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  Includes note "VVG regarding GDC for June 1985".
- Shaulis seminars, scholars, awards received, 1980-1995 (Box 24, Folder 21)
- Proposed Promotion and Research fund, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 22)
- Research, by others, 1982-1986 (Box 24, Folder 23)
- Don Crowe – And Vitacultural Research speech, June 30, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 24)
- N.L. Partridge based research, ca. 1988-1989 (Box 24, Folder 25)
- Research, includes others, ca. 1940-1976 (Box 24, Folder 26)
- Economics, 1939-1969 (Box 24, Folder 27)
- Merbein Counts, 2 vines, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 28)
- Shoot count, ap dom., Fredonia Experiment Station, North of Willows, book, May 1976 (Box 24, Folder 29)
- Section III, 2 vines, yield estimate and 1972 Merbein Counts, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 30)
- Fredonia, NY vines, 4 photographs, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 31)
- Pom Cards (Box 24, Folder 32)
  Includes Pom 6496 September 1978, Pom 6491September 1978, Pom 6459, Pom 6848 1981,Pom 6489 September 1978, Pom 2156 GDC
- Vineyard photographs, research sheets, ca.1967-1978 (Box 24, Folder 33)
- Statistics for Merbein Counts, ca. 1977 (Box 24, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, mainly regarding research, 1951-1981 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  Includes letters to Mark Kliewer about trellis systems in cold climates. Also information regarding terminology for grapevine canopies and a paper titled Some Observations on Terminology Useful in Describing Grapevines. Also scans of some of these items on a disc.
- “Vineyard management for a More Competitive Cost Per Ton Of Grapes”, draft, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 36)
- "Natural Resources 420, NRG Vineyard site selection - Use of GIS for quantitative analysis of site suitability in the Keuka Lake district. ", 1994 (Box 24, Folder 37)
- Approaches to Grape Quality Assessment at Simi Winery by Diane Kenworthy (Box 24, Folder 38)
- Summary statements and idea, ca 1962-1970 (Box 24, Folder 39)
- Data sheets, 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 40)
- Cold injury at vineyard lab, Fredonia, NY, 1969-1970, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous data, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 42)
- Joe Mass, Canoga vic., Delaware, slides, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 43)
- West Tier data sheets (Box 24, Folder 44)
- “Report on 1977 research on the two Major Long-Term Factorial Experiments on Grapevine Management”, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 45)
- Writing to do, 1971-1977 (Box 24, Folder 46)
- Vineyard financial management, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 47)
- Pruning data, ca. 1969-1977 (Box 24, Folder 48)
- Concord grapes, yield analysis, vine spacing, pruning (includes Pom 4389), ca. 1959-1985 (Box 24, Folder 49)
- Pom 5137, slides, water spot on Rougeon, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 50)
- Hargrave data, Cabernet Sauvignon, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 51)
- Conferences, conventions, and meetings, 1958, 1969-1996 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  Only item from 1958 is photo of Gladiolus meeting April 12, 1958. Includes ca. 1980 photo of Nelson Shaulis and Bob Pool
- Viticultural experiments and vineyard management, ca. 1978-1985 (Box 24, Folder 53)
- Nelson Shaulis notepads, ca. 1982 (Box 24, Folder 54)
- Robert Carian, California grape grower, ca. 1984 (Box 24, Folder 55)
- Temperature damage, ca. 1962-1985 (Box 24, Folder 56)
  Includes 1966 article Der Einfluss der Temperatur und der Sonnenstunden auf den Blütezeitpunkt der Reben and 1978 article Die Frosthärte der Rebe in Abhägigkeit vom Wittergsverlauf während der Winterruhe with a translation
- Articles - Liberty Hyde Bailey, etc., ca. 1944-1978 (Box 24, Folder 57)
- Pesticide applicaton, 1979-1983 (Box 24, Folder 58)
  Includes 1983 applicator certificate and 1979 Regulations Concerning Use and Application of Pesticides
- Lake Erie viticultural area petition, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 59)
- Finger Lakes appelation of origin, letter, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 60)
- Meteorological study of Geneva data, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 61)
- Programs regarding viticulture and vine size, 1979-1981 (Box 24, Folder 62)
- Slides and photographs, ca. 1970-1976 (Box 24, Folder 63)
  Includes 1976 Concords, 1979 canopies, 1972 no oxidant stipple, White Riesling glyphosate, 1970 Concord ethrel treatment
- Shoot and vine growth, 1946-1985 (Box 24, Folder 64)
- Economic and crop yields, 1975-1984 (Box 24, Folder 65)
- List of viticultural journals for binding, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 66)
- NEC-9, Long Island, Riverhead, NY, July 11, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 67)
- Grape petiole analysis, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 68)
- R. Musselman, Forsline, and Kender paper, NY work, 1983-1984 (Box 24, Folder 69)
- Reducing the Period of Juvenility by Grafting Grape Seedlings, Charles O. Foerster, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 70)
  Includes 4 attached color photographs
- Mechanization and implements, 1959-1982 (Box 24, Folder 71)
  Includes 2 photographs of Holmes harvester, 1976
- 1982 Japan visit, 1981-1982 (Box 24, Folder 72)
- Work in progress, January 1983 (Box 24, Folder 73)
- Slides with faulty legends (Box 24, Folder 74)
- Aggrotechnical effects on wine quality, Ben-Ami Bravdo, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 75)
- National Grape, 1955-1956, 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 76)
- Geza Hradzina reporting on Welch's Grape Juice data, 1973-1978 (Box 24, Folder 77)
- Viticultural products, ca. 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 78)
- Pom cards - Distribution and production, 1951-1972 (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Cultivars, ca. 1950-1966 (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Spontaneous sports, 1956-1964 (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Irradiation and induced sports, 1954-1966 (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Morphology and anatomy, ca. 1966 (Box 25)
- Pom cards- Leaf symptoms (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Roots, rootstocks, and soils (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Growth regulators (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Growth retardants (Box 25)
- Pom cards - Potted vines (Box 25)
- Letter describing why Shaulis' viticulture book was never published, March 4, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 0)
- A Role of Alar in the Culture of Concord, ca. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Boron deficiency, 1947-1980 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Manganese, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Vineyard fertilizer studies - Nitrogen, Phosphorous, Potassium, 1920-1959 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Vineyard fertilizer studies - Nitrogen, Phosphorous, Potassium, 1960-1976 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Vineyard Fertilization - By Tradition or by Vine Nutrition (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Grape nutrition research and education needs, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  Includes questions regarding fertilizers
- Centennial, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Port Wine, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- South Africa, 1987-1989 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Terminology, 1986-1988 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Descriptor list for grape vine varieties and Vitisspecies, OIV Paris, selected parts (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Terminology, 1986-1988 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Terminology, July 1986 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Terminology - Worksheets, ca. 1985 (Box 26, Folder 15)
- Terminology - Chart 1 (Box 26, Folder 16)
- Terminology - Gail and Emily, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 17)
- Terminology - Miscellaneous, November 26, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 18)
- Terminology - Outline and manuscript, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 19)
- Essay data, use, Lucie Morton book, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 20)
- Script data, preliminary and not used, Lucie Morton book, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 21)
- Data, final, Lucie Morton book, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 22)
- Essay literature, Lucie Morton book, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 23)
- Essay literature, not used, Lucie Morton book, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 24)
- Photos, Lucie Morton book, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 25)
- Rootstock Effects on Grapevine Canopies, essay preliminary script (Box 26, Folder 26)
- Terminology- Definitions and comments, 1973-1995 (Box 26, Folder 27)
- Terminology - Table 2, chart 1 of 4, 1979-1996 (Box 26, Folder 28)
- Terminology - Manuscript tables 1,2,3,4, 1987-1991 (Box 26, Folder 29)
- Terminology - Table 2, ca. 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 30)
- Terminology - Tables 1,2,3,4, ca. 1991 (Box 26, Folder 31)
- Terminology - Richard Smart, 1988-1991 (Box 26, Folder 32)
- Terminology - Miscellaneous pages of notes, Richard. Smart, ca. 1985-1989 (Box 26, Folder 33)
- Terminology - Table 1,3, 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 34)
- Terminology - Table 4, with Richard Smart data, ca. 1981-1987 (Box 26, Folder 35)
- Terminology - Table 1, brief, 1985-1988 (Box 26, Folder 36)
- Terminology - Table 3, canopy form and canopy density, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 37)
- Terminology - Tables 1,2,3,4, July 1988 (Box 26, Folder 38)
- Approaches, best practices, glossary, and formulas, ca. 1997 (Box 26, Folder 39)
- Terminology, July 1989 (Box 26, Folder 40)
- Terminology, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 41)
- Terminology - Manuscript, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 42)
- Terminology tables, etc. (Box 26, Folder 43)
- Terminology - for Reno, 1988-1992 (Box 26, Folder 44)
- Terminology - Charts 1,2,3 with 7 classes, 1988, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 45)
- Terminology - Chart 3 of 4, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 46)
- Terminology - Chart 4 of 4 with numbers (Box 26, Folder 47)
- Terminology - Text and charts 1,2,3, VVG, ca. 1988 (Box 26, Folder 48)
- Terminology - Chart 2 or 4, only 1 copy with 7 classes, ca. 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 49)
- Script material - terminology, June 1985 (Box 26, Folder 50)
- Terminology, 1984, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 51)
- Terminology, literature cited, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 52)
- Canopy terminology, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 53)
- Slide notes - Washington and California grapes and mulch (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Slides and notes - presentations, 1983-1988 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Empty slide frames with notes written on them - Glyphosate field trip, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Photographs - California and Washington Box, color gradient plates (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Negative - California and Washington Box (Box 27, Folder 5)
  single negative of aerial landscape
- Slide notes - Viticulture book (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Slide notes - Reno carousel, etc. (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Slide notes - A-E (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Slides and photos - canopy, 1950-1988 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Photographs -viticulture, reprints, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 10)
- Photographs and drawing - Bulletin 816, vineyard weed spray boom (Box 27, Folder 11)
- Pruning weights from Gordon DeGolier, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Slides, slide notes, and research, glyphosate work by John Harker, 1979-1980 (Box 27, Folder 13)
- Negatives - Richard Smart New York work, Two Days in Life and photos from his thesis, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 14)
- Photographs and diagram - Minimal pruning, Peter Clingeleffer, February 22, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  Note "valuable"
- Photographs - photographs of vineyard labs, mostly aerial, ca. 1970 (Box 27, Folder 16)
- Slides - Dikeman, Joy, BTI and LEGS, 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 17)
- Slides and commentary - foliage/canopy development, Al Weiss, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Slides - miscellaneous Loomis and vineyard 21, 1973-1982 (Box 27, Folder 19)
- Slides - freezing, glyphosate, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 20)
- Slides - Boron excess and defoliation, Dikeman and Joy, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 21)
- Slide notes - Viticulture book (Box 27)
- Slide notes - Reno carousel, etc. (Box 27)
- Slide notes - A-E (Box 27)
- Slides and photos - canopy, 1950-1988 (Box 27)
- Photographs -viticulture, reprints, 1983 (Box 27)
- Photographs and drawing - Bulletin 816, vineyard weed spray boom (Box 27)
- Pruning weights from Gordon DeGolier, 1984 (Box 27)
- Slides, slide notes, and research, glyphosate work by John Harker, 1979-1980 (Box 27)
- Negatives - Richard Smart New York work, Two Days in Life and photos from his thesis, 1974 (Box 27)
- Photographs and diagram - Minimal pruning, Peter Clingeleffer, February 22, 1988 (Box 27)
- Photographs - photographs of vineyard labs, mostly aerial, ca. 1970 (Box 27)
- Slides - Dikeman, Joy, BTI and LEGS, 1982-1983 (Box 27)
- Slides and commentary - foliage/canopy development, Al Weiss, 1972 (Box 27)
- Slides - miscellaneous Loomis and vineyard 21, 1973-1982 (Box 27)
- Slides - freezing, glyphosate, 1989 (Box 27)
- Slides - Boron excess and defoliation, Dikeman and Joy, 1984 (Box 27)
- Slide - Reno Carousel, oversized, loose in carousel box, 1979 (Box 27)
- Slides - Reno carousel, 1961-1984 (Box 27)
- Slides - Reno carousel, loose in carousel box, ca. 1964-1989 (Box 27)
- Slides - Slides for December 28, 1987, carousel 2, 1948-1987 (Box 27)
- Slides - Publications, San Diego, ca. 1948-1986 (Box 27)
  Includes some Japan slides
- Slides - Publications, San Diego, loose in carousel box (Box 27)
  Includes one slide "VVG, diagram from Sakai lab regarding cold hardiness"
- Slides - Fredonia studio slides, extra book slides, 1973 (Box 27)
- Slides - A day in the life of two grapevines and other slides, 1974-1975 (Box 27)
- Slides - Tour New York farms, 1971 (Box 27)
- Slides - Spray equipment, 1950-1965 (Box 27)
- Slides - Shaulis box 1, 2 plots (Box 27)
- Slides - 2 presentation slides, 1993 (Box 27)
- Slides - Insects, 1950, 1973 (Box 27)
- Equipment photograph and postcards (Box 27)
- Photographs -Boron deficiency, 1940 (Box 27)
- Slides - A, Tuskeegee speech, July 11, 1979, 1959-1970 (Box 27)
  See also, slide notes A-E folder. Includes Concords, Biotron
- Slides - B, July 11, 1979, 1958-1976 (Box 27)
  See also, slide notes A-E folder. Includes Concords, Alar, temperatures
- Slides - C, Ithaca #1, RCK 348, 1949-1973 (Box 27)
  See also, slide notes A-E folder.Includes, temperature, shoots, yield, water potential
- Slides - D, Ithaca #2, POM 307, 1951-1976 (Box 27)
  See also, slide notes A-E folder.
- Slides - E, POM 307, December 1, 1977, 1950-1974 (Box 27)
- Slides - F, POM 307, December 8, 1977, 1961-1977 (Box 27)
- Slides - 2,4-D use, 1947-1967 (Box 27)
- Slides - Oil - DN, 1949-1951 (Box 27)
- Slides - ICA and injury, 1949 (Box 27)
- Slides - Crag-I, 1952-1953 (Box 27)
- Slides - Chloro-IPC, 1952 (Box 27)
- Slides - Simazin, 1957-1958 (Box 27)
- Slides - Karmex, 1949-1966 (Box 27)
- Slides - Weed Equipment, ca. 1950 (Box 27)
- Slides - Karmex - Injury, 1953-1960 (Box 27)
- Slides - 2-3,6 Herbicide, 1949-1958 (Box 27)
- Slides - Karmex, over-all, 1949-1959 (Box 27)
- Slides - Unlabeled section, 1945-1963 (Box 27)
- Slides - Aeriel, 1948 (Box 27)
- Slides - Grafting, 1944-1962 (Box 27)
- Slides - General vineyard scenery and vineyard lab, 1949-1968 (Box 27)
- Slides - Out-of-state, 1947-1957 (Box 27)
- Slides - Grape rooting, 1953-1963 (Box 27)
- Slides - Soils, boron, 1975-1989 (Box 27)
  Note - Erosion in the vineyard February 1983 and February 1984, July 1993 Fredonia for Nelson J. Shaulis speech
- Slides - Box 1, winter injury, 1957-1966 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, vigor (shade), 1954-1965 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, management analysis (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, 10-year chart and statistics (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, regeneration (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, pruning, 1950-1965 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, trellising and training, 1949-1966 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, training including double trunk and trellis, 1951-1965 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, hail injury, 1954 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1, fruit maturity, 1947-1956 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1 layering, 1960 (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 1 sampling (Box 27)
- Slides - Box 2, Gibrel, seedless, 1957-1960 (Box 27)